接通六号线  赌侠马华力
Check your six, Maverick.
你的长官正在山顶呼叫你
This is your captain up and on the mountain.
请注意  女士们先生们
Listen up, ladies and gentlemen.
亡命徒已经逃离一个半小时
Our fugitive has been on the run for 90 minutes.
我们正在下水道搜索  这次别把脚打湿了
We're in the pipes. Let's keep our feet dry this time.
丛林电台
Jungle radio,
编号1-D-B呼叫 [美军用语]
This is one Delta Bravo.
发现疑犯  请求支援
Eyes on suspect. Requesting backup, over.
请求部署开启
Requesting permission to deploy
激光放射防盗系统
Laser-activated radioactive immobilizer.
请求驳回
Permission denied.
别玩了  理查德
Really. Richard.
在开始排练剧本前
I have all of these new lines to learn
我还有这么多台词要看
Before my play goes into rehearse.
正靠近目标
I'm goin' in.
如果再靠近一点
If that comes any closer,
我就把这玩意儿给拆了
You're gonna have Black hawk down on your hands. Oh!
这是在干什么
What's all this?
警察战术训练
Police tactical training.
爸爸  你记得要签
Oh, hey, dad. Did you get a chance to sign
我前几天给你的家长许可单了吗
That permission slip I gave you the other day?
你还没学会伪造我的签名吗
Haven't you learned to forge my signature yet?
信用卡的话  当然
Credit cards? Yes.
家长许可单  还没有
Permission slips? No.
学校公民课要求
It's my civics' class.
每个学生要在市政府机关
Every student has a 3-day volunteer internship at one of
做三天的志愿者实习工作
The city's agencies--
执法机关  环卫机构  消防部门
Law enforcement, sanitation, fire.
去消防部门吧  他们工作最有规律
Oh, go with fire. They have the best calendars.
我选了执法机关
I went with law enforcement.
贝克特探长已经答应
Detective Beckett already said it's cool
-我到警局去当志愿者了  -那么
- If I volunteer down at the station.  - Oh, well,
作为纽约市警察局志愿队的一员
As a member of the NYPD volunteer squad
我很乐意为你做一些介绍
I would be happy to show you the ropes.
事实上  贝克特探长明天早上
Actually, Detective Beckett is giving me
会带我熟悉一下工作
My orientation course tomorrow morning.
那么我很荣幸能和你  拼车上班
Then I would be honored to carpool with you
或者合坐一辆的士
Or share a cab.
卡塞尔
Castle.
初步检测显示
Prelim suggests the victim died
死者因胸口近距离中弹  一枪毙命
Of a single gunshot wound to the chest at close range.
-有搏斗的迹象吗  - 这里有挫伤
- Any signs of struggle?  - Contusions coming up here...
还有这里
And here.
但也有可能是
But it's likely a result of
跌下垃圾槽而致
His tumble down the trash chute.
怎么了
What?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我无法用鼻子呼吸
Well, I can't breathe through my nose.
不幸的是我的嗅觉很灵敏
I happen to have a very acute sense of smell.
忍忍吧  卡塞尔
Suck it up, Castle.
真警察碰到过比这更糟的
Real cops deal with worse.
没错  更别提法医了
Yeah, not to mention medical examiners.
你知道在我出去约会之前
Do you know how long I have to shower
要洗多长时间的澡吗
Before heading out on a date?
不知道  但如果想找人计时的话
No, but if you need someone to time it f you,
-我很乐意为你服务  -找到了
- I'd be happy to--  - Found it!
肯定是跌下来时  从他上衣里掉出来的
It must have fallen out of his jacket on the way down.
没错  就是他
Yep, that's our guy.
他叫萨姆·帕克
All right the name is Sam Parker.
驾照上有他的住址  在康涅狄格州
And the driver's license has his address placed in Connecticut.
可能是来这见朋友
Maybe he's visiting someone in the building.
-你是说路过  -我是莱恩
- You mean dropping by,  - Ryan here.
谢了  老兄
Thanks, bro.
埃斯波西托在15楼
Esposito's up on 15.
他说找到案发现场了
Says he found out where our guy was shot.
好  我们走吧
All right. Let's go.
从血迹来看  死者是在这里被枪杀的
From the blood spatter, our guy was shot right here.
然后
Then...
头朝下被推下垃圾槽的
He was shoved head first down the chute.
一个自己善后的凶手
A killer who cleans up after himself.
很像《美国狂魔》[电影名]
Very "American Psycho."
他可能是想
He probably wanted
神不知鬼不觉地把尸体扔出去
To get out of the building unnoticed
以为这几天不会有人
Figured that the dumpster wouldn't be emptied
来清理垃圾槽
For a couple of days.
他没想到7楼的一个住户
He didn't count on a tenant on the seventh floor--
一个辣妹  在扔比萨盒的时候
A hottie-- seeing the body drop
-看到尸体掉下来  -她吓坏了吗
- As she threw out her pizza box.  - Is she distraught?
我很会安慰人
Because I can be very comforting.
通知鉴证小组了吗
C.S.U.s?
-正赶过来  -周围的人没有听到枪声
- Team's on its way.  - Neighbors didn't hear the shot.
平价消音器
Ah. Poor-man's silencer.
他肯定是从这堆东西里找到这个
He must have picked it up from this pile here
-完事之后又扔了  -聪明
- And then thrown it back when he was done.  - Resourceful.
整齐体面的郊区居民
How did a clean-cut suburban guy
为何会离家这么远
End up this far from home
被杀害  然后被弃尸垃圾堆
Dead and thrown out with the trash?
好了吗  我冲啦
Are you ready? Here we go.
我知道阿丽克西斯已经跟你说过了
I know Alexis already talked to you.
我只想确认  你真的不介意她
I just wanted to make sure that you're really okay
-到这里来  -如果介意我就不会答应
- With having her here?  - I wouldn't have said yes if I wasn't.
是这样没错  但你很忙
Well, yeah, but you're busy,
我只是不想她打扰到你
And I just don't want her to be in the way.
大卡塞尔才会打扰到我
Big Castle is the one who likes to get in the way.
我很肯定小卡塞尔会很有趣
I'm sure little castle will be a pleasure.
萨姆·帕克  38岁
Sam Parker, aged 38
和妻子海伦住在康涅狄格州
Lives in Connecticut with his wife Helen
还有两个孩子
And his two kids.
妻子正赶往停尸房认尸
Wife's en route to the morgue to I.D. the body.
我们联系了租赁办公室
We contacted the leasing office,
住户名单上没有萨姆·帕克这个人
And they don't have a Sam Parker listed as a tenant.
那么他确实是在拜访某人
So he probably was visiting someone.
正在调查  还没发现
Uniforms are canvassing. No hits yet.
鉴证科在破解指纹
C.S.U.'s working to untangle the prints,
但垃圾槽是公用的  可能有很多指纹
But since it's a common room, there's probably dozens of them.
然而  垃圾槽的把手
However, the chute handle,
门把手和苏打瓶 都被擦干净了
Doorknob and soda bottle were all wiped clean.
好  我们去停尸房见见他妻子
All right, let's go visit the wife at the morgue.
也许她能告诉我们  他今晚为何而来
Maybe she can tell us what he was doing in the city tonight.
即使不知道  其中也必有蹊跷
And if she doesn't know, that tells us something, too.
给你
Uh, here you go.
刚冲的  好烫  好烫
Oh, fresh. And hot and hot and hot.
他没给我冲咖啡
He doesn't make me coffee.
你没事吧
You okay?
不管你经验多丰富  做这种事也不轻松
It's never easy, no matter how much experience you have.
天哪
Oh, my god.
我是凯特贝克特探长  纽约警局的
I'm Detective Kate Beckett. I am with the NYPD.
我们感到非常抱歉
I'm very sorry for your loss.
你们知道凶手是谁吗
Do you have any idea who did this?
我们正在尽力追查
We are doing everything we can to figure that out.
不好意思  我们正在进行认尸
Um, excuse me. We're in the middle of an identification.
她就是来认尸的
That's why she's here.
那你是
And you are?
我是来认我丈夫的遗体的
I'm here to identify my husband.
天哪
Oh, my god.
抱歉  这是你丈夫
Excuse me, your husband?
你和死者是什么关系
What's your relation to the victim?
我是他的未婚妻
I'm his fiance.
等等  你刚刚说什么
I'm sorry. What did you just say?
我是他未婚妻
I'm his fiance.
老兄  东窗事发了
Dude, you are so busted.
我都不知道怎么打发她们走
I don't even know how to get the two of them out here.
我是怕
I'm just scared that--
那是死者的妻子吗
Is that our vic's wife?
未婚妻
Fiance.
妻子在那边
The wife is over there.
再说一遍
Come again?
未婚妻
Fiance.
妻子
Wife.
-麻烦了  -我知道  他够享受的吧
- Oh, boy  - I know. Isn't it delicious?
那我们先和谁谈
Okay, who do we talk to first?
我知道这很令人痛苦  里德小姐
I know this is difficult, Ms. Reed.
但请允许我们问你几个问题
But if we could ask you a few questions.
你认识帕克先生多久了
How long did you know Mr. Parker?
帕克
Parker?
萨姆
Sam.
他叫杰克  杰克·霍兰
His name is Jake, Jake Holland.
根据他的驾照
According to his, uh, driver's license,
他叫萨姆·帕克
It's Sam Parker.
这全是谎言  甚至名字也是吗
It was all a lie...even his name?
你们是怎么认识的
Where did the two of you meet?
因为工作
At work.
我的闺蜜说  她的部门有位不错的男士
A girlfriend of mine said that there was this great guy
问我想不想见见他
In her department, and did I want to meet him.
-你俩最后一次通话是何时  -今天下午
- And when did you two last speak?  - This afternoon.
他打来说在回城的路上
He called to say he was on his way back to the city.
他父亲在一家偏远的医院
His father is in the hospital upstate.
他患有晚期的老年痴呆症
He has late-stage Alzheimer's,
杰克都会去看他  每...
And Jake would drive up to see him every...
我太蠢了
I'm so stupid.
他周末是跑回去见
He was spending the weekends with...
他妻子
His wife.
你原本今晚要和他见面
So you were intending to see him tonight?
我们原本打算叫个外卖  看场电影
We were going to get takeout and watch a movie.
一位邻居在走廊上拦住我
A neighbor stopped me in the hallway
告诉我警察来过
And told me that the police had been there,
但我打电话去问  却没人能回答我
But when I called, nobody could tell me anything.
我现在知道原因了
I-I guess now I know why.
因为他真名叫萨姆·帕克
Because we I.D.him as Sam Parker."
太平间的工作人员
Somebody at the morgue
证实从他家里抬出一具尸体
Confirmed that a body had been picked up at his address,
所以我赶了过去
So I went down there.
当他求婚时
When he proposed,
我告诉好友  她并不支持我
I told my best friend, and she was all,
"你们只相识短短半年而已"
"You've only known him six months."
但我不在乎
But I didn't care.
他是我的真命天子
He was the one.
他怎么可以这样做
How could he do this?
这太疯狂了  这女的是谁
This is insane. Who is this woman?
萨姆绝不会  他爱我
Sam would never. He--he loved me.
我们的孩子是他的一切
Our kids meant everything to him.
远不止这些
Apparently there was more to it
显然这不仅是婚外情  帕克夫人
Than just the affair, Mrs. Parker.
你丈夫在工作中使用假身份
Your husband was using a false name at his job.
我不明白  为什么他要这样做
W-well, I don't understand. Why would he do that?
我们正在调查
We're still trying to figure that out.
据了解  他因为工作关系认识里德小姐
But from what we understand, he met Ms. Reed at his office.
他半年前到那里工作
He--he started there about six months ago.
他放弃了以前公司的升职机会
He had been passed over for promotion at his old firm.
在绿色新技术领域的工作机会不是很多
And there are not a lot of opportunities in green solutions,
所以即使离家很远  他还是接受了
So he took the job even though it was in the city.
绿色新技术  是指环保意识吗
Green solutions as in environmentally conscious?
他为公司做咨询服务
He did corporate consulting--
如何减少浪费  节约资源
How to reduce waste, save energy.
这是他所热衷的
It was a passion of his.
非常令人钦佩
That's very commendable.
工作回家  往返太远
Well, all that working and commuting
让他很疲倦  因此他找了一间廉租房
Were running him ragged, so he found a cheap sublet.
虽然艰苦  但如果困难解决了
It was hard, but if it all worked out,
我们也将搬到城里
We were gonna move down to the city
我们就能一家团聚
So that we could all be together.
帕克夫人  你是否知道
Mrs. Parker, did you have any idea
你丈夫有婚外情
That your husband was having an affair?
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
为什么没发现蛛丝马迹
Why didn't I notice the signs?
我们育有两个孩子  没有保姆
We have two children together. We do not have a nanny.
所以我所有的时间
So every second of every minute of my day
都围着我的孩子
Is about my kids.
有事我就打他的手机
And if the was an issue, I'd call Sam on his cell phone,
他每次都接
And he would always answer.
我从不
I never...
从未想过我会在这  捍卫我的婚姻
Never thought I'd be sitting here justifying my marriage.
妻子这边  是"每周电话联络"
With the wife, it was "only call my cell during the week" routine.
未婚妻这边  他撒谎
With the fiance, he pulled out the trusty.
"医院打电话不方便"
"I can't call you from the hospital" act.
如果我一小时不打电话给女友报到
Man, my girl friend freaks out
她会抓狂的
If I don't check in, like, every hour
你真的每小时报到
You do check in, like, every hour.
甚至更频繁
Sometimes more.
这家伙让两个女人都相信
This guy had both of these women believing
她们是他的唯一真爱
That they were his one and only.
人们相信他们愿意相信的事
People believe what they wanna believe.
直到真相揭开的那天
Till the dead truth sets in.
你觉得其中一个发现萨姆脚踏两条船
What, you think one of them caught out what Sam was doing
当她发现并不是他的唯一
And didn't take too kindly when they discovered
就残忍地杀了他
They weren't the only woman in his life.
我不知道  她们好像都很震惊
Mm. I don't know. They seem pretty shocked to me
没错  我也这么觉得
Yeap, to me too.
但我们得调查现有的所有事实
But we gotta cover all of our bases.
两人的不在场证明都有疑点
Both of them had soft alibis.
妻子说当孩子们在楼上睡觉时
The wife said that she was watching TV
她在看电视
While the kids were upstairs sleeping,
未婚妻说她独自一人在家
And the fiance said that she was home alone
等着见他
Getting ready to meet him.
查查电话和账单  看有什么发现
We'll run phone and financials, see if anything pops.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我可以  -好的
- Could I run...- Right.
你认为他会是真心的吗
Do you think he'd really gone through with it?
什么真心
Through with what?
娶莎拉  如果他没被杀
Marrying Sarah, if he hadn't gotten killed.
在使用假身份的情况下还有胆量
Well, that was a pretty big rock he put on her finger.
向她求婚确实令人震惊
With the fake identity he had set up,
对一个已婚者来说
The county clerk's office never would've flagged him
政府办公室是不会给他发结婚证的
For someone who was already married.
但是萨姆在认识莎拉之前  就化名杰克
Yeah, but Sam was pretending to be Jake before he met Sarah.
我不明白为什么要用假身份
I don't understand the fake identity.
也许要得到这工作
Maybe to land the job.
我明白要在简历上造假
I understand fibbing on your resume.
但改名换姓
But changing your identity?
这样不合理
The math doesn't quite add up for me.
我觉得什么不合理呢
You know what math doesn't add up for me
两个妻子
Hmm. Two wives.
-一个妻子太多  -两个太多
- One wife too many for you?  - Two wives too many.
这点不合理只是针对
Seems like the common denominator in that equation
你
Is you.
好消息
Good news.
最终我还是去听了你介绍的
I'm finally embracing the lecture you gave me
关于有机食物重要性的讲座
On the importance of organic food.
你在给我做午餐吗
You made my lunch?
我不会将你的健康交给
You think I'm gonna let you risk your life on
自动贩卖机和变味的甜甜圈
The vending machines and stale doughnuts of the break
怎样
What?
你看起来  长大了
You look so... Grown-up.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really?  - Really.
奶奶说人靠衣装
Well, gram said presentation is vital.
我忘了拿手机
Oh, I forgot my phone.
你也经历过吗
That ever happen to you with me?
有天发现儿子已经长大成人了
One day, you look and you see your boy is all grown-up?
事实上  我还在等那一天的到来
I'm still waiting for that moment, actually.
是我自讨苦吃  对吧
I set you up for that, didn't I?
好  这是资料室
Okay, so this is the property room. It's where
在犯罪现场找到的物件
We keep all the items that we find at a crime scene
但却不能作为证据  存放在这里
That aren't classified as evidence.
有点像失物招领处
Sort of like a lost and found?
算是吧
Um, sort of.
为什么受害者的家人不认领回去呢
Why don't the victims' families claim this stuff?
贵重物品就有人认领
Well, loved ones are aware of the big-ticket items,
像戒指和手表
Like rings and watches.
但像太阳眼镜和打火机之类的
But things like sunglasses and lighters,
通常无人认领
Those usually go unclaimed.
这些是案件编号吗
Are these case numbers?
没错  所以工作就是
Exactly. So the idea is to get rid of
把这些东西处理掉  放进仓库
All of this stuff and stick it into storage.
在此之前  先分类
But before we do that, we have to catalog it
以防有人认领
Just in case someone comes in with a claim.
就是需要每个物品的标签
Okay, so you need a description of every item
还有相应的案件编号
Along with its corresponding case number
输入数据库
Downloaded into the database.
我知道  这跟你当志愿者的初衷
And I know that this isn't exactly
有很大出入
What you were thinking of when you asked to volunteer,
我们很缺人手  这大有帮助
But we're low on manpower, and this would be very helpful.
别担心  这地方在我手上
Don't worry about it. This place is gonna be
将变得井井有条  到时你肯定认不出
So organized when I'm done, you won't even recognize
一定是那样的
I bet I won't.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我爸爸有时很烦人
I know my dad can sometimes be a handful.
"有时"  我指的是每时每刻
And by "sometimes," I mean all the time.
但我想你知道  别担心我
But I want to let you know don't have to worry about me.
我会做得很好
I'm all about getting the job done.
-贝克特  -头
-Beckett.   - Sir.
-怎样  -阿丽克西斯  她很好
- Well? - Alexis? She's fine.
她上幼儿园的第一天
You know, her first day of preschool,
我躲在外面的树丛里一整天
I hid outside in the bushes all day
就为了确保她没事
Just to make sure she was all right.
我儿子第一次去夏令营
The first time my son went to summer camp,
我一路尾随那辆巴士
I followed the bus all the way to get around.
你们俩不是太贴心就是太变态
You two are both either very sweet or very creepy.
楼管让我们搜了萨姆·帕克的公寓
Super let us into Sam Parker's apartment.
杰克·霍兰的公寓
Jake Holland's apartment
同一个人
Same guy.
对  只是想让大家清晰明了
Yeah, just trying to keep it straight for everyone.
话说回来  没有任何挣扎的痕迹
Anyway, there was no signs of a struggle,
-而萨姆的袋子  -杰克的袋子
- And Sam's bag was... - Jake's bag.
自他从康涅狄格州探望家人回来时
Still sitting by the door from when he came home
就一直放在门旁
From visiting his family in Connecticut.
这就解释了为什么在他被杀后
Which explains why we found the Sam Parker wallet on him
能找到他的钱包
When he was killed,
而在他的柜子上我们找到这个
As supposed to this one we found in his dresser.
杰克·霍兰的钱包
Jake Holland's wallet.
里头有他纽约的身份证  工作证
It's got his driver's license With his New York address, work I.D.
全部家当
--The whole shebang .
拜托告诉我这是旧式的双面相框镶嵌
Oh, please tell me that's the old double-sided picture frame gag.
可爱的未婚妻  简单摇身一变成为
The lovely fiancée, which can easily be swapped out for...
妻子和孩子
The wife and kids
预防他们突然来大城市探望爸爸
Should they ever visit daddy in the big city.
好消息是  我们在厨房的柜台上发现这个
The big news is, we found this sitting on the kitchen counter.
这里有一条你会想听的语音信息
There's a voice mail you're gonna want to hear.
我不会让你脱身的
I'm not gonna let you get away with this,
你连一块垃圾都不如
You worthless piece of trash.
如果你今晚不给我回电
If you don't call me back tonight,
那我下一个电话就要打给海伦
Then my next call is to Helen.
看来有人发现了萨姆的双重身份了
Someone caught on to Sam's double life.
查过号码  姓名查尔斯·德佩翠
Ran the number. Belongs to one Charles Depetro.
德佩翠  那是他妻子的娘家姓
Depetro? That's his wife's maiden name.
她的驾驶照上有登记
It's hyphenated on her driver's license.
查理是海伦的哥哥
Charlie is Helen's brother.
他发现了萨姆的秘密
He found out what Sam was up to.
并决定清除垃圾
And decided to take out the trash.
德佩翠先生  我能明白你保护妹妹动机
Mr. Depetro, I can understand the instinct of protection.
如果我有妹妹  而她的丈夫背叛她
If I had a sister and her husband was cheating on her,
我也会想把他干掉
I'd want to set him straight, too.
这不是我留言的原因
That's not why I left the message.
你知道萨姆背叛海伦了吗
Did you know that Sam was cheating on Helen?
她昨晚打电话告诉我才知道
Not until she called me last night.
并告诉我他被杀了
And told me he'd been killed.
那你说"我不会让你脱身"
Then what did you mean when you said
这话是什么意思
"I won't let you get away with this"?
他欠我钱
He owed me money.
萨姆向你借了钱
So Sam borrowed money from you?
两万块  说要用来还房贷
20 g's. He needed it to cover the mortgage.
但他之前已经拿房子做了抵押
He had already borrowed against the equity in the house.
那他给你什么回复
And what was the arrangement?
他说他需要几个月
He said he needed a couple months.
当他在城里找到一份新工作时
When he started the new job in the city,
我以为他会赚到更多钱
I figured he'd be making more dough.
海伦不知道这个
Helen didn't know about this?
他不想让她担心
He didn't want her to worry,
只要他把钱还我了 我答应不说出去
And as long as he paid me back, I said it'd be our secret.
那他还了吗
And did he pay any of it back?
没有  他总说自己的薪水更少了
Not a cent. He kept saying he was pulling in less money.
我觉得他在撒谎
I thought he was lying.
这份工作离家那么远  为什么要做
Why take the job that far from home
让海伦一个人来照顾孩子
And force Helen to deal with the kids on her own?
结果证明他根本不是为了家人
Comes out now he wasn't doing it for his family.
他只想瞒着我妹妹  玩婚外情
He wanted the freedom to cheat on my sister.
调查过哥哥的不在场证据
Brother's alibi checked out.
当萨姆或者杰克被杀时他工作到很晚
He was working late when Sam/Jake was shot.
帕克收入方面有消息吗
Any word on the Parkers' financials?
有  他们用支票还了拖欠的贷款
Yeah, they're a paycheck away from defaulting on their mortgage.
萨姆大舅子说过  萨姆的新工作
You know, the brother said that Sam was pulling in
薪水更少了  那如果萨姆缺钱
Less money at his new job. If Sam was strapped for cash,
为什么要辞去工作  而做薪水少的
Why would he quit the job he had to take one that paid less?
他妻子不是说他放弃了升职机会吗
Didn't his wife say he was passed over for a promotion?
可能是有关自尊
Maybe it was a pride thing.
对  但你要另外租房  更不用说煤气费
Yeah, but you factor in the sublet not to mention gas.
这自尊的代价可真高
That's a high price to pay for pride.
对  不要低估男性自尊的脆弱性
Yeah, well, never underestimate the fragility of the male ego.
-这就是偏见  -不  不要
- Oh, see? That's just a stereo...- Don't, don't. That's--
她在挑衅我们  好吧
She is bating us, all right?
无视她  她的女巫力量就没用了
Just ignore her. She'll lose her witchy powers.
想得美
You wish.
走  去一趟帕克的办公室
All right. Let's go off to Parker's office.
丢东西了
Lose something?
在  哪里
Um... Where--where, uh...
我的扫帚在哪里
Where's my broom?
我见过
I was looking.
反正我不是那样的
For the record, I did not.
我不太清楚  或许我该看过
I don't know. Maybe I should've seen it.
他的履历完美得像是假的
His resume was almost too good to be true--
在伯克利和斯坦福商学院时是班上的尖子
Top of his class at Berkeley, Stanford business school.
他要说这种谎  肯定是非常需要这工作
He must have really needed this job to lie so bad.
那你想不到他撒谎的其它原因了
So there's no other reason you can think of as to why he lied?
-想不到  -你聘请他时
- No. - When you hired him,
你有调查过他的推荐人吗
Did you look into any of his references?
当然  探长  我是亲自跟他们联系的
Of course I did, detective. I called them all myself.
只有一堆热情的推荐
And I got nothing but glowing recommendations.
推荐一个不存在的家伙
For a guy who didn't exist.
如果你还有的话  我想看他的履历副本
I'd like to take a look at copy of his resume if you still have it.
我会让人力资源部发邮件给你
I'll have human resources e-mail it over to you.
还有一个问题  你知道帕克先生
Uh, before we go, did you know that Mr. Parker
正在和你的一个员工恋爱吗
Was romantically involved with one of your employees?
莎拉  知道  她是我最好的工程师之一
Sarah. Yeah, she's...one of my best engineers.
有什么戏剧性事情吗
Ever notice any drama,
在办公室派对里醉酒打闹  之类的
Drunken fighting at an office party, that sort of thing?
没  没有
No, never.
他们看上去感情相当好
They actually seemed like a pretty solid couple.
她现在肯定备受煎熬
And she must be going through hell right now.
抱歉  您所拨打的号码无法接通
We're sorry. The number you have reached is not in service.
请检查你的号码或稍后
Please check the number or try your call--
这是最后一个
That's the last one.
他给的每一个推荐人都打不通
Every single reference he gave is suddenly out of service?
据他老板所说
Well, according to his boss,
这些号码半年前都能打通
They were all up and running six months ago?
那么是谁接的那些电话
So who was answering the dummy lines?
去申请调查这些号码
Let's get a warrant for all these numbers.
咱们得知道机主是什么人
I'd like to know who they were registered to.
好
Ok.
这家伙似乎是不择手段  想得到这工作
This guy went to so pretty serious lengths to get this job.
这肯定有不寻常的意义
They must have amazing dental.
真不知道你怎么学会这些的
I don't know where you got this work ethic,
但绝对不是因为我
But it certainly was not from me.
干得如何
How's it going?
还不错  那台电脑刚开始有点问题
Pretty good. The computer was a little glitchy at first,
但那是因为没有人来升级软件
But that's because no one had run a software update
大概有  两年
In, like, two years.
还有  它中了毒  而我不得不杀毒
Plus, it picked up some viruses I had to zap.
我发现让你做这工作太大材小用了
I am realizing that you are way overqualified for this job.
告诉过你她是个聪明女
Told you she was a smarty.
但我有一个问题
But I do have one question.
像你之前所说的
Like you said before,
这里多数东西都没什么价值
Most of the items here are pretty junky and meaningless.
但我找到了这个
I did find this, though.
是吹牛相册
Oh, it's a brag book.
就能到处跟别人夸自己的孩子了
So you can brag about your kids.
以前我钱包里有  现在用手机存了
I used to have one in my wallet. Now it's on my phone.
有些照片很旧
Some of the pictures are really old,
像是很珍贵的
Like they're one of a kind.
只要它还没有贴上标签
It seems like something worth returning,
似是应该要物归原主
Only it wasn't tagged or anything.
对  但问题是  没有案件编号
Yeah, but the problem is, is without a case number,
就很难找到这是哪位受害者的
It's difficult to find out who the victim was
怎样还给他家人
And how to get this back to the family.
好吧  那就要收到贮存箱里对吗
Okay. So then it just goes in the storage box, right?
这样好了
I'll tell you what--
我给你一份名单
I'll give you a list
列出所有可能负责这案子的警官
Of all the detectives who possibly worked this case.
拿这些照片给他们看  或许会有人记得
Show them the pictures. Maybe it'll strike up a memory.
-如果他们忙就不要打扰  -你在说你自己
- Only don't bother them if they seem busy. - You're one to talk.
十分感谢
Thanks so much.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-这是什么  -爸爸
- What's this? - Dad!
好  我马上过来
Okay, I'll be right there.
未婚妻来了  她想谈谈
The fiancee's here, she wants to talk.
玩得开心
Have fun.
在太平间时我就觉得她很眼熟
I knew she looked familiar at the morgue,
但我一开始不敢肯定
But I couldn't place it at first.
你是说昨晚
So you're saying that last night
不是你第一次看见海伦·帕克
Wasn't the first time you had seen Helen Parker?
对她的脸有些印象
Well, there was something about her face.
然后我就想起
And then it hit me--
几周前在杰克的公寓前我见过她
I had seen her in front of Jake's apartment a couple weeks ago.
她那时候正离开大楼吗
Was she leaving the building?
不  她坐在车里  车停在街对面
No, she was sitting in her car across the street.
-你确定是海伦·帕克  - 我现在很确定
- And you're sure it was Helen Parker? - I'm sure of it now.
在街对面有一辆车
Positive identification
你能确定就是她
From all the way crossed the street in the car?
我记得是因为她当时看我的眼神
I made a note of it because the way she was staring at me
很  怪异  好像她在打量我
Was... Creepy, like she was sizing me up.
里德小姐  过去的24小时对你来说
Ms. Reed, the past 24 hours have been...
无法承受  至少可以这么说
Overwhelming to say the least.
在经受精神创伤后  证人的记忆
It's not uncommon for witnesses' memories
出现混乱是正常的
To be confused after a traumatic event.
我们需要绝对肯定
We just need to be absolutely sure.
我知道自己看到什么
Look, I know what I saw.
她坐在一辆银色的凯雷德里
She was sitting in a silver Hybrid
看着大楼前方
Staring at the front of the building.
跟你的未婚夫说过这事吗
And did you tell your fiancé about this?
没有  那时候我打消了念头
No. At the time, I just dismissed it.
可现在...  我忍不住担心
But now... It makes me wonder
如果整件事情里我是唯一一个
If I'm the only person in the whole situation
浑然不知的人  会发生什么事
Who didn't know what was really going on.
银色的凯雷德
Silver Hybrid.
海伦应该知道她丈夫的婚外情
I guess Helen did know about her husband's affair.
那就有了强烈的动机
That would be a pretty strong motive.
大老远来就因为她说了这么离谱的事
You came all this way because she told you some crazy story
我把车停在了公寓外面
About me being parked outside the apartment?
帕克太太  我们不会放过任何线索
Mrs. Parker, we have to take every lead seriously.
你们想过没有  也许是她编造的
Did you ever think that maybe she made this up
为了分散对她的注意力
To take the attention off of herself?
她特别提到了你的车
She was specific about your car.
银色凯雷德  那是...  就像
A silver Hybrid? That's--that's like saying
有人穿黑色鞋子一样
Somebody was wearing black shoes.
那也还是没能回答我们的问题
That still doesn't answer the question.
没有
No.
萨姆在公寓的半年里
In the six months Sam had the apartment,
我从没去过那里
I never went there.
你从未放下孩子  和丈夫来个约会之夜吗
You never popped down just once for a date night?
从康涅狄格开车去也不是很远
I mean, Connecticut's not that far a drive.
当你有两个不到十岁的孩子时
Well, when you have 2 children under the age of 10,
不是周末  跑去赴约几乎...
Popping down for date night midweek is...
是不可能的
Nearly impossible.
萨姆每周末都回家
Sam came home every weekend,
那时我就能见到他
And I would see him then.
好吧  我们需要调查
Okay, well, we just needed to check.
很可能是里德小姐弄错了
It's possible that Ms. Reed was mistaken.
你可曾想到  或许她才是知道
Did it ever occur to you that maybe she was the one
他在撒谎的那个人
That knew he was lying?
我们会考虑每种情况
We're considering every scenario.
上个月有许多挂断的电话
We got a lot of hang-ups last month.
你们觉得那是巧合吗
Do you think that's a coincidence?
你跟萨姆说过吗
Did you tell Sam about it?
说过  他说只是电话推销员
I did. He said it was telemarketers.
但是  是她
But it--it was her.
你如何肯定是她
How can you be sure?
她有我们家的电话号码
I know she has our phone number.
萨姆被杀后她打过电话
She's called since Sam was killed.
莎拉打给你的
Sarah called you?
她问关于葬礼的细节  你能相信吗
She called about the funeral details. Can you believe that?
如果她认为能够出席葬礼
If she thinks she's gonna show her face here,
就大错特错了
She is sadly mistaken.
莎拉只打来过一次吗
Was that the only time you heard from Sarah?
不  她今早又打过电话  还留了可笑的留言
No, she--she called this morning and left some ridiculous message
有关她送给萨姆的东西  她想收回
About getting things back from Sam that she had given him,
不停说什么钢笔
And then on and on about some pen
是她祖父的
That had been her grandfather's.
我们已结婚十年零八个月
We were married for ten years and eight months.
如果她认为半年的婚外情
If she thinks that her 6-month affair
能和我们的婚姻相比
Can hold a candle to that...
我不会给她任何东西
I'm not giving her anything.
漫长的车程
That was a long drive.
我明白为何他会在市里租了公寓
I can see why he got the apartment in the city.
我调查了帕克工作职位的基本情况
So... I did some background on Parker's job situation.
结论是他的前任雇主
Turns out that his old employer,
康涅狄格环保公司  消耗殆尽
Connecticut Solutions, has been circling the drain.
在过去几年中
Over the last couple of years,
被他的新任雇主夺去一半的市场
They've lost half their market share to his new employer,
纽约回收
New York Recycle.
听起来像萨姆离开了输的一方
Sounds like Sam was abandoning a sinking ship.
加入赢的一方
To join the winning team.
想必是纽约回收有了新技术
Supposedly New York Recycle came up with some new technology
结果成了游戏主宰者
That turned out to be a game changer.
似乎一开始  两位总裁就已棋逢敌手
Apparently these two C.E.O.s have been major rivals from day one.
像比尔·盖茨和斯蒂夫·乔布斯
Like Bill Gates and Steve Jobs,
柯比和勒布朗
Kobe and Lebron...
茱丽和安妮斯顿
Jolie and Aniston.
明白了  竞争对手
We get the picture. Rivals.
是的  所以萨姆伪造了简历
Yes. My point was, maybe that's why Sam fixed the resume
他认为如果纽约回收知道他来自
He didn't think that New York Recycle would hire him
康涅狄格环保  就不会雇用他
If they knew he was from Connecticut Solutions.
言之有理
Well, that makes sense.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding me.
谢谢  你帮了大忙
Uh, thank you. You've been very helpful.
申请调查萨姆简历上的号码
Hey, the warrants just came through on the numbers
还有推荐人的号码  有结果了
On Sam's resume? His references' phone numbers?
都是他上一个公司注册的
They're all billed and registered
账单也是寄去康涅狄格环保公司
To Connecticut Solutions, his old firm.
为何他们申请这些电话
Okay, why would they set up dummy phone lines
提供伪造的推荐信
And give phony recommendations?
他们希望萨姆被雇用
They wanted Sam to get hired.
他并非对升职不理不睬
He wasn't passed over for a promotion.
他被安插在纽约回收  做商业卧底
He was planted at New York Recycle as a corporate spy.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我得好好想想
I'm just trying to get my head around this idea.
他在劳动节野餐会上组织
I mean, this is the guy who organized the potato sack race
马铃薯麻袋竞赛
At the Labor Day picnic.
有重要的间接证据表明
Well, there's considerable circumstantial evidence
他是前任雇主派来的
That he was planted here by his former employer.
只是还没有具体证据
We just don't have the proof yet.
显然  没人比我更想要
Well, obviously, no one wants to get to the bottom of this
追根究底
More than I do.
我们会完全配合你们的工作
So you'll have our complete cooperation.
你认为康涅狄格环保的目标是什么
What do you think Connecticut Solutions was after?
是我们的电池回收技术
It's our battery recycling technology.
我确信你们都知道不应该
I'm sure you both know you're not supposed to dump
把电池扔进垃圾筒
Your batteries in with your trash.
电池需要完全处理
Batteries need to be disposed of properly,
否则  酸溶液和重金属析出...
Or else the acids and the heavy metals will leech out into--
-进入地下水  -没错  正是
- And get into the water table. - Exactly, yes.
问题是  储存电池废物是很昂贵的
The problem is, storing battery sludge can be quite expensive
但我们想到了办法循环利用
But we figured out a way to actually recycle the stuff.
当你争取回收旧电池的合同时
So when you bid on a contract to haul aw old batteries,
能降低出价
You can do it cheaper.
那样康涅狄格环保
Which is why Connecticut Solutions
就要分你半个市场
Lost half of its market share to you.
说到底  是他们无力还击
The bottom line is, they can't compete.
莎拉·里德是开发这项目的
Was Sarah Reed on the team of engineers
技术工程师之一吗
That developed that technology?
是的  没错
Yeah, that's right.
很可能因为这样  萨姆·帕克
Well, that's probably why Sam Parker went out of his way
故意接近她  很聪明
To romance her--for access. That's pretty smart.
请原谅  你是说他卑鄙吗
Pardon me, but don't you mean despicable?
两者并不互斥
The two aren't mutually exclusive.
介意我们的信息技术组
Would you mind if our forensic I.T. team
看看莎拉和萨姆就是杰克的电脑吗
Took a look at Sarah's computer and Sam's--Jake's--as well?
或许能告诉我们
They should be able to tell us
是否危及了你的安全
Whether your security was compromised
是否私自占有了什么
And whether he got a hold of anything proprietary.
我们愿全力配合
Anything we can do to help.
好  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
信息技术组已拿到莎拉和萨姆的电脑
Forensic I.T. has taken possession Of Sarah and Sam's computers.
公司里有很多商业秘密
You know, there's a lot of corporate secrets
派间谍去偷我能理解
I could see sending a spy to steal,
偷偷摸摸的  就为了电池废物
But all this skulking around for some battery sludge?
像那个人说的  这也是生意
Well, like the man said, it's a business like any other.
不论谁经营康涅狄格环保公司
But whoever runs Connecticut Solutions
都需要解释究竟是怎么一回事
Is gonna have a hell of a lot of explaining to do.
是真的吗
Is it true?
里德小姐
Ms. Reed?
他们说的  是真的吗
What they're saying, is it true?
我不能说细节
Look, I can't go into details,
但有证据表明杰克试图偷取信息
But there's evidence that Jake was trying to steal information.
都是在做戏
Then it was all an act?
那...  不代表他不在乎你
Now that--that doesn't mean he didn't care about you.
那就是那个意思
That's exactly what it means.
他从没爱过我
He never loved me.
他一直都是在利用我
He was just using me the whole time.
这家伙很厉害
This guy was good.
在他硬盘的隐藏分区里
He was running a secret e-mail client
运行着一台秘密电邮客户服务器
From inside a hidden partition in his hard drive.
说英语  我的搭档不太懂这个
English? For my partner here.
为防止有人会察觉  他设计的装置
He set things up so that he could send emails outside
以便于他向公司以外的网络发邮件
Of the company network in case anyone ever came snooping.
什么样的邮件
What kind of emails?
我解析电脑  但是这个
I speak computer. This however...
看起来像化学分子式
Looks like chemistry.
-他是跟特定人物联系吗  -是
- Was he communicating with anyone in particular? - Yeah.
所有的邮件都是给同一个人的
All these-mails were to the same guy.
Aberman@conn-sol.net
Aberman@conn-sol.net.
安迪·伯曼
Andy Berman.
他是康涅狄格环保的总裁
He's the C.E.O. of Connecticut Solutions.
他肯定就是萨姆的报告对象
He must have been who Sam was reporting to.
几个月前他们互通了很多电邮
They exchanged a bunch of e-mails a couple months ago,
然后到萨姆被杀前都没有联系
Then nothing till the night Sam was killed.
最后一封说什么
And what'd that one say?
"给我打电话  我们需要谈谈"
"Call me. We need to talk."
是的  这是事实
Okay, yes, it's true.
那个晚上萨姆发邮件给我
Sam emailed me the other night,
-我打电话给他  -用公用电话
- And I called him. - From a pay phone?
在我家附近的加油站
At a gas station near my house.
很像秘密间谍啊
Very cloak and dagger of you.
他说要在市里见我
He said he needed to meet me in the city.
他说终于查到
He said he finally figured out
纽约回收是如何成功的
How New York Recycle was pulling it off.
那么你承认派他去卧底
So you admit that you planted him there
偷取他们的电池回收技术
To steal their battery technology?
他们出价总比我们低
They've been underbidding us left and right,
抢走了我们的生意
Stealing our business.
分享他们的回收技术
Getting our hands on their recycling method
能让我们公司分到客观的利润
Was a way to level the playing field.
但他们不愿分享  所以我就给萨姆
They weren't gonna share it, so I offered Sam
一百万  只要他能掌握核心技术
A $1-million payday if he could get a hold of it.
等他在电话里说任务完成了
And when he called and said he completed his mission,
你马上赶过去
You rushed right over.
我和萨姆  早就算完成了
The thing about Sam is, he and I had been down this road before.
什么意思  他之前就告诉你得手了
What do you mean? He--he'd told you he'd found it before?
根据他给的资料
I wasted hundreds of thousands on research and development
我在研究和开发花了无数的金钱
With the stuff he brought me.
这个化学分子式根本就不完整
The chemical formulas were never complete.
所以当工程师试图完善它
So when my engineers tried to fill in the blanks
测试它时  我们总是失败
And test them, we failed every time.
最终  我们耗尽资金
Finally, we ran out of money,
所以几个月前
So a couple of months ago,
我不得不和萨姆切断联系
I had to cut Sam loose.
既然萨姆不再为你工作
If Sam wasn't working for you,
他在电话里说了什么
What was he calling about?
他说要给我看点东西
He said he needed to show me something.
-是什么  -我不知道
- What?- I don't know.
我驾车到市区他的公寓见面
I drove into the city to meet him at his apartment,
但我停车之后
But as I pulled up,
就看到门口有许多警察
There were cops all over the entrance.
我感觉不妙
I got a bad feeling about it,
所以我转身离开  驱车回家
So I turned around and I drove home.
非常有趣的故事  伯曼先生
That's very interesting story, Mr. Berman.
但我有个不同的结尾
But I have a different ending--
你上楼走到萨姆的公寓
One where you went upstairs to Sam's apartment
他告诉你终于找到了正确的分子式
And he told you that he finally found the real thing.
于是你对自己说
You said so yourself.
你的公司已经无力支付他一百万美元
Your company didn't have the $1 million to pay him.
那么你能做的事只有一件
So you did the one thing that you could.
杀了他再偷走分子式
You killed him and you stole it
只有孤注一掷才能拯救衰败的公司
In a desperate attempt to save your sinking company.
我要求打电话给我的律师
I would like to call my lawyer now, please.
你编故事的方式  相当漂亮
That was pretty cool, the way you filled in the story there.
我可能还比不上你
I think I must be rather off on you.
比我想的还要黑暗
That sounded dirtier than I meant it.
贝克特
Hey Beckett.
接警说康涅狄格那边有情况
Dispatch just got a call out of Connecticut.
纽黑文警局  两位女士发生口角
New Haven P.D. have two women involved in an altercation.
说到黑暗
Speaking of dirty...
接受询问的女士们要求
And the ladies in question are asking for you
在做笔录前  要见你一面
Before they're taken in for booking.
找我  为什么
For me, why?
不是吧
Oh, no.
就是
Oh, yes.
莎拉·里德和海伦·帕克分别被控
They're holding Helen Parker for assault
袭击他人和非法闯入私人领域
And Sarah Reed for trespassing.
妻子和未婚妻的战争
A wife and fiancee catch fight.
允许我们在路上买点爆米花
Please tell me we can stop for popcorn on the way.
卡塞尔
Castle.
就是这里  独立书房
That's it, the detached office,
当帕克太太遇到她时
When Mrs. Parker confronted her,
就吵起来了
An altercation ensued.
她想抢我的包
She tried to rip my purse off my arm.
几乎让我肩膀脱臼了
Almost dislocated my shoulder.
里德小姐
Ms. Reed
你在帕克的办公室干嘛
What were you doing in the parkers' office?
她不把钢笔还我
She wouldn't give me back my pen.
-你的钢笔  -我的祖父留下的
- Your pen?  - My grandfather's fountain pen.
我把它给了杰克
I gave it to Jake wh--
萨姆  他的名字叫萨姆
Sam! His name was Sam!
给他的时候  不知道他是个骗子
I gave it to him before I knew he was a lying sack.
然后她就不还我了
And she wouldn't give it back to me.
我就在办公室里找  那什么也没有
I looked for it in the office. There was nothing there.
我根本不知道她在说什么
I have no idea what she's talking about.
是吗  那这是什么
Oh, really? Huh. Well, then what do you call this?
那在办公室吗
That was in the office?
是的  就在抽屉里
Yes. It was right there in the drawer.
我不知道她怎么会忘记
How she could've missed it, I don't know.
除非她在撒谎  而且从来没找过
Unless, of course, she was lying and never bothered to look.
里德小姐  我理解你的感受
Ms. Reed, I understand how you're feeling,
但闯入别人的家里
But breaking into someone's home
这是我祖父的钢笔
No, this is my grandfather's pen.
早知如此我绝不会送给杰克
I never would've given it to Jake if I had known.
女士们  我们能否先将
Ladies, I'm wondering If maybe we can put
这惹人厌的插曲放在一旁
This whole nasty episode behind us.
她闯入我家  谁知道她还偷了什么
She broke into my house. God knows what else she stole.
介意看下你的包吗
Do you mind if I take a look at the purse?
没问题
Not at all.
高兴了
Happy now?
可以了吗  这事就算过去了
Is everyone okay? Can we all just walk away?
如果再让我看到你
If I ever catch your face around here
得了吧  你就大声喊出来
For crying out loud, give it a rest!
怪不得他会得溃疡
No wonder the guy had an ulcer.
如果是我和你结婚  我也会
I would, too, if I was married to you.
溃疡
An ulcer?
你说什么  你这个疯子
What are you talking about, you crazy lunatic?!
听着  听着  女士们
Look! Look! Hello. Ladies, look!
我知道你们都很生气
I understand that you're both angry
而且感觉被背叛
And feeling betrayed,
但互相责骂对方  有用吗
But taking it out on each other. Isn't going to help.
你们可以起诉对方
So you can both press charges
让情况更糟糕
And make a bad thing worse
或者冷静地离开
Or you can calm down and walk away.
选择二是有时间限制的
Option number two is a limited-time offer.
-爱你  -回头见
- Love you. - See ya.
别说你又在休息室里睡了一晚
Please tell me you did not sleep in the break room again.
我回家了
I went home.
只是忍不住去想昨晚那事
Just can't stop thinking about that fight last night
要是说我也是  会不那么想念我吗
Ooh, would you think less of me if I said, me, too?
我一直在想  莎拉离那很远
I kept thinking that that was a long way for Sarah to go
只是为了拿钢笔
Just to pick up that pen.
还有溃疡什么的
And that whole thing with the ulcers was
我知道了  上演《绝望主妇》
Oh, I know. That was a great "Desperate Housewives" moment,
莎拉可是刺激了海伦一通
The way Sarah just rubbed Helen's face in it.
问题是  哪有什么溃疡
The thing is, There's nothing about an ulcer.
在蕾妮尸检报告中
In Lanie's autopsy report.
萨姆十分健康
Sam had a clean bill of health.
那莎拉说的又是什么
Then what was Sarah talking about?
他们正在调查
The boys are looking into it right now.
但是据萨姆的日程安排来看
But according to Sam's date book
过去三周
He had doctor's appointments every Tuesday
他每周二都和医生有预约
For the last three weeks.
如果他有忧郁症的话
Well, if he was being a hypochondriac about it,
他们就不会马上告诉他有溃疡
They would've told him right away he didn't have an ulcer.
那么他周二下午一点在干什么
So what was he doing every Tuesday at 1:00 p.m.?
另一个女人
Another woman?
医生办公室
So the doctor's office
没有萨姆·帕克和杰克·霍兰的病人记录
Has no patient records for Sam Parker or Jake Holland.
已经确认萨姆用过汽车服务
Car service Sam was using confirmed
目的地是医生办公室
That he gave the doctor's office as his destination
当他安排汽车时
When he was scheduling the cars--oh
谢谢  艾丽斯
Thanks, Elise.
但我和司机谈过
But I talked to the drivers.
萨姆一上车就改变了目的地
Sam changed the destination once they picked him up.
第一周他去了
The first week he headed out
长岛的居民区
To this residential address out in long island.
第二周去了
The next week he drove out to
在帕拉默斯的纽约回收加工厂
New York recycle's  Processing plant up in Paramus.
最后一周到纽瓦克港口
And then last week, he hit the port out in Newark.
萨姆不想莎拉知道他的诡异行踪
Sam wouldn't have wanted Sarah to get on to his 007 routine.
也许他不告而别是去做间谍了
So maybe he was slipping away to do his spying.
在长岛呆了几个小时
At some hours on long island?
另一个女人
So another woman.
她和萨姆在纽瓦克港
She and Sam were
浪漫地在纽瓦克港一起散步
Taking Long, romantic walks at Port Newark.
为什么你不相信
Why you gotta ruin the dream?
听着  萨姆最后一刻改变目的地
Listen, Sam was changing his destination last minute
是因为他在隐藏什么
With the car service because he was trying to hide something.
我们来看看这些地址
So let's look into the addresses
看看他为什么
And see why he
要欺骗萨拉
Felt the need to give Sarah a cover story.
州法规定每工作五小时  休息十分钟
State law requires a 10-minute break every five hours.
谢谢  爸爸  我早想喝了
Thanks, dad. I needed this.
资料室的调查进展如何
So how goes your property room sleuthing?
不太顺利
Not amazing.
贝克特给你的
Oh, no. What happened to that
警官名单查得如何了
Uh, list of detectives Beckett gave you?
最后一个线索刚才也断了
I just hit my last dead end.
更重要的是  你尝试过了
Oh, well, what's important is, is that, uh, you tried.
我知道
I know.
只是我真的很想把那些照片
I just really wanted to get those pictures
还给受害者家人
Back to the victim's family.
如果这些是你随身携带的照片
I mean, I'd want them if they were pictures
我也希望能够找回来
That you'd carried around.
如果你想象的画面是
If you are imagining a scenario where I am
我不在了  无法关注你一举一动
No longer here and watching over your every move
保护你免受危险
And protecting you from every danger,
那我保证  绝不可能发生
I can assure you, that will never happen.
我刚才只是说觉得那个很重要
I'm just saying, I think it's important.
不  你说的没错  但是记住
No, you're right, but remember,
这么多东西无人认领是有原因的
There's a reason why a lot of this stuff goes unclaimed.
是啊  在我剩下的时间里
Yeah. I guess I just need to focus on cataloging
应该把注意力放在分类上
For the rest of my time here.
在你知晓之前  就会从执法部门退休
And before you know it, you'll be retired from law enforcement
回到高中继续学习
And back in the eleventh grade.
谢谢爸爸
Thanks, dad.
为什么  不谢
For what? You're welcome.
你给我指了条新线索
You just gave me a new lead.
我会帮你把可可喝完的
So I'll finish your cocoa.
两组家庭关系
Two relationships.
你能想象这种压力吗
Can you imagine the stress of trying to pull that off?
是的
Yes.
从纯文学观点来看
Uh, from a literary point of view.
你们发现了什么
Hey. What'd you guys find?
我们按照片进行调查
Well, we canvassed using a picture.
遇到纽瓦克港口的一名工作人员
We came up with a alongshore man in port Newark
他记得萨姆
Who remembered Sam.
似乎萨姆当时在询问旅客名单
Apparently he'd been asking about shipping manifests.
没什么可疑
Sounds random.
这个人帮不上忙  萨姆就离开了
The longshoreman couldn't help him, so Sam moved on.
第一个周二去的地方呢
What about the address from the first Tuesday?
有好消息
Oh, here's where  gets good.
长岛那个地址住着一位单身母亲
The long island address is the residence of a single mother--
劳伦·布兰斯顿和六岁的女儿
Lauren Bramston-- and her 6-year-old daughter.
我早就说了  是另一个女人
I told you it was another woman.
三角恋变成了四角恋
Our love triangle just became a love square.
不  还是三角恋  换了名字但是...
Nope. Still a triangle. Different name, but that's...
未婚妻  莎拉·里德
The fiance, Sarah Reed.
看起来萨姆不是唯一隐瞒身份的人
Well, it looks like Sam wasn't the only one hiding his identity.
订婚  恋情
The engagement,  the relationship,
我们已经知道这是一场骗局
We know they were all fake.
证明爱情不存在可是很难的  贝克特探长
Love is a hard thing to disprove, detective Beckett.
这是你真实驾照的复印件
This is a copy of your real driver's license.
你的社保卡
And this is your social security card.
一份纽约回收中心的受雇记录
And this is the employment record from New York Recycle
是用假身份登记的
Under an assumed identity.
一点不像新起点
Nothing like a fresh start.
我们还查到
We did a little digging.
纽约回收中心不是第一个
Turns out New York Recycle isn't the first company
你用假身份上班的公司
You've worked for under a new identity.
我必须维持生计
A girl's gotta make a living.
我是这么想的
Here's what I'm thinking--
兰斯·卡尔伯格发现了萨姆是个间谍
Lance Carlberg figured out that Sam was a spy.
他联系了你  专业的商业间谍
He contacted you, an expert in corporate espionage,
让你去搞定他
And asked you to intercept him.
我只做了分内的事
I was just doing my job.
骗人不算犯罪  是不是  探长
Leading a man on isn't a crime, is it, detective?
-的确不算  -我没问你骗人的事
- Should be. - I'm not looking into the leading on part.
我问的是谋杀
I'm looking into a murder,
你去过萨姆的公寓
And you had access to Sam's apartment,
你受雇"照顾好"他
And you were hired to take care of him.
我只受雇阻止他
I was hired to get in his way.
我本来应该假装已经
It was supposed to look like I had access
取得了机密信息
To classified information.
所以当我和他调情的时候
So when I struck up a flirtation,
他认为这种关系会给他机会
He thought the relationship would give him the access he needed.
一旦你们在一起  你的计划是怎样的
Once you had the relationship, what was the plan?
我只需偶然把笔记本电脑
I just had to leave my laptop
落在他的公寓
Lying around his apartment once or twice.
有个周末把门卡落在了他的衣服里
My keycard ended up in his laundry one weekend.
男人都认为他们很聪明
Men think they're smart.
方法就是让他们不停地自以为是
The trick is to keep letting them think it.
那么你的电脑里有什么
Um... So what was on the computer?
兰斯给萨姆部分的化学式
Lance was feeding Sam these partial chemical formulas.
他认为这能让康涅狄格的研究毫无进展
He thought it would keep Connecticut solutions going in circles.
为什么不甩了他
Why not just fire him?
为什么不一石二鸟
Why not kill two birds with one stone?
绊住对手  还能把康涅狄克弄得一团糟
Keep the enemy close and run Connecticut into the ground.
是什么让你觉得
And what makes you think
萨姆陷入了你的圈套
That Sam was falling for your routine?
开始我也疑惑
Well, I wondered at first,
因为他从不跟我上床
Because he wouldn't sleep with me.
后来我意识到他忠于他妻子
And then I realized that he was being faithful to his wife.
就佯信了他"我很守旧"的理由
So I pretended to buy his whole "I'm old-fashioned" thing.
他以为他在耍我
He thought he was playing me.
他确实
He was.
这是萨姆的验尸报告
This is Sam's autopsy report.
萨姆没有得溃疡
Hmm. Sam didn't have an ulcer.
他总是去看医生
He was seeing a doctor for it.
不  这是个幌子  他耍了你
No, that was just a story.  He made you.
不可能  如果他骗我  我能看得出来
No way. I would've been able to tell.
我不想打破你化名的美好愿望
Oh, I hate to burst this little "alias" bubble you got going on,
但是萨姆找到了你在长岛的房子
But Sam found your house in Long Island.
他早就知道你不只是个轻浮的工程师
He knew you were more than just a flirty engineer.
为了不引起你的猜疑  他演了好久的戏
He played along not to arouse suspicion,
但我想你已经知道了吧
But I think you already knew that.
你知道他是在玩你  而他
You knew that he made you and that he found
发现了秘密方法  所以你杀了他
The secret method, and that's why you killed him.
我想这听起来像是
I think that sounds like a...
一个精彩谍中谍故事  但是有个问题
Great spy versus spy story, But there is one problem.
萨姆被杀那晚  我在女儿的独奏会上
The night Sam was killed, I was at my daughter's recital,
约二十名家长能够证明
And there's about 20 other parents that can vouch for that.
我喜欢她  她适合当凶手
I like her... For the murder.
你看到她疯子般的眼神了吧
You see that crazy look in her eye?
那是疯狂杀手的眼神
That's crazy-killer look.
莎拉的不在场证明证实了
Yo,  Sarah's alibi checks out.
凶案发生时
Dance teacher puts her in the front row
舞蹈老师请她坐在前排
At the time of the murder.
她还是那副疯狂的眼神
She's still got crazy eyes.
他从没爱过她  她也从没爱过他
He never loved her, she never loved him,
而他们都以为在玩弄对方
And they both thought that they were playing each other.
这还是不能说明谁是凶手
Which still doesn't explain who killed him.
我们忽略了什么
We're missing something.
那支笔
The pen.
如果莎拉跟萨姆的感情是假的
If Sarah's relationship with Sam was a fake...
她怎会把祖父的钢笔送给他
Then why did she give him her grandfather's special pen?
还有昨晚莎拉在萨姆的办公室
And what was Sarah really looking for
真正想找的东西是什么
In Sam's office last night?
什么都没有  我还是想不通
Nothing. This doesn't make any sense.
我们已经检查了莎拉的包
We went through Sarah's purse.
如果有重要东西  我们早就发现了
If there was something in it, we would've found it.
卡塞尔  你在想什么
Castle,  what are you doing?
我在构思一个场景
I'm writing a scene.
假设萨拉找到了要的东西
Let's say Sarah found What it was she was looking for.
东西拿在手上
She had it in her hand.
这个时候她听到海伦进来了
That's when she would've heard Helen coming out of the house.
她就必须不顾一切
She would've had to have
避免她手里的东西被发现
Gotten rid of whatever it was that she found...
很精彩  你想构思下东西的位置吗
Great. You want to write the part where we find it?
这样海伦永远都不会知道
So Helen would never know.
你看看这是什么
Ah. What do you know?
还通着电源
Power mode is still on.
我们需要点胶带
We're gonna need some tape.
这些是死者
These are the pics that our Vic took
假装去看医生时拍下的
While he was supposedly at the doctor.
根据纽约回收中心的说法  他们把
According to New York Recycle, they ship
电池废渣运到在帕拉默斯的回收工厂
Their battery sludge up to the recycling plant in Paramus.
去帕拉默斯可不必乘船
You don't need a boat to get to Paramus.
笨蛋秘方  他们没有处理废渣
Secret method, my ass. They weren't processing it.
他们把商标换了  然后倒掉废渣
They were switching labels and dumping it.
萨姆像是艾琳·布劳克维奇[电影《永不妥协》女主角]
That Sam was quite the Erin Brockovich, wasn't he?
根本就没有回收电池的秘密方法
There was no secret method to battery recycling.
你们把废渣装到货物驳船上
You shipped the sludge out on cargo barges
然后倒入海中
And dumped it in the ocean.
由此省下的存储费和处理费
The money you saved on storage and processing
就进入了你的口袋
You just put into your own pocket instead.
我知道我的权利
Listen, I know my rights.
我什么话都不会说
And I don't have to say anything.
你把一大批货物卖给了客户
You sold a bill of goods to your customers.
你向他们保证说他们会拯救世界
You promised them that they were gonna help save the world.
而你为了钱  丧尽天良
Instead you poisoned it for money.
怎么回事  卡尔伯格
What happened, Carlberg?
萨姆质问你  威胁说要揭发你吗
Sam confront you, threaten to ruin you?
我没有杀任何人
I didn't kill anyone.
你
And you...
你没有证据
You have no proof.
事实上  我有
Actually, I do.
我们做了弹道测试  结果吻合
We ran ballistics. It's a match.
在你家楼外的垃圾桶里发现的
We found it in the dumpster outside your apartment building.
如果你把这个也回收了  也许能逃脱罪责
Had you recycled, you might have gotten away with it.
你丈夫被谋杀的当晚
The night that your husband was murdered,
他回到办公室
He went back to his office
去取他收集的最后一点证据
To grab the last few pieces of evidence he had collected,
当时  卡尔伯格已经怀疑他了
And by then, Carlberg had already become suspicious.
当他发现你丈夫
When he realized that your husband
要联系旧老板请他帮忙揭露丑行时
Was contacting his old boss for help in exposing his company,
卡尔伯格想用封口费买通他
Carlberg attempted to buy his silence,
但是萨姆不买账
But Sam wouldn't accept the bribe.
当然不会  萨姆不是那种人
Of course not. Not Sam.
你说环境问题
You said that the environment
是你丈夫最关心的事
Was the most important thing to your husband.
他为了保护环境而牺牲
Well, he died trying to save it,
我们觉得你应该知道这个
And we thought that you should know that.
谢谢
Thank you.
看看吧
Check it out.
环保局把纽约回收中心查封了
The E.P.A. is shutting down New York Recycle.
安娜·诺尔斯  不  我不认识
Anna Noles? No, I don't know any Anna Noles.
我认识
I do.
好吧  让她上来
Uh, yeah, send her up.
安娜·诺尔斯是谁
So who's Anna Noles?
我发现的照片是她妈妈的
The pictures I found belonged to her mother.
是吗  你怎么发现的
Really? How'd you track 'em down?
是因为老爸说的那些话
It was something you said, dad,
关于我从执法部门退休的事
About me retiring from law enforcement.
让我想到  要是最初查案的警官
It got me thinking, what if the officer who had
退休了怎么办
Originally worked the case had since retired?
干得漂亮
Nice work.
你能结案让我刮目相看
I'm very impressed you were able to close this case.
谢谢  我知道这不如
Thank you. I-I mean, I know it's not like
你做的工作重要  但是我
The important stuff you do, but I--
当一个人失去亲人
You know, when a person loses someone,
这些是最重要的
This is important.
我猜就是她
I bet that's her.
也许你该跟她谈谈
You know, maybe you should talk to her.
谢谢
Thank you.